

Serena Tomassetti

🛱 15th April 1989

Zürich, Switzerland

் L'Aquila, Italy

C-Permit

CONTACTS

\$\\$ +41 76 728 42 70

□ serenatomassetti001@gmail.com

serenatomassetti.com

in linkedin.com/in/serena-tomassetti

SKILLS

HCI, User Research, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Information Architecture, Usability Test, Datadriven decisions.

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Figma, Sketch, Abstract, Balsamiq, Zeplin, Look Back, Mouseflow, Hotjar, Stargate, PowerBi, Tableau, Google Analytics.

LANGUAGES

Italian: native

English: fluent

German: professional

PASSIONATE ABOUT

Design, art, photography, skiing, hiking, traveling.

VOLUNTEER

UX Specialist at Catchafire.

SUMMARY

Resourceful User Experience Designer with broad practice in design and customer experience. I promote a user centered approach across companies. Recognized for critical thinking, accuracy to details, self management. I am a curious person, a hungry reader and traveler, with a high interest in technology and innovation.

EXPERIENCE

UX Researcher & Designer • SwissRe

Zürich · Nov 2021 · Present

Plan and conduction of user research for the redesign of B2B data visualization Corporate Real Estate platforms, part of Data Engineering & Analytics Team. Workshops for ideation, crossfunctional alignment, decision making. Design the platforms in low/high fidelity, and prototype. Usability testing.

Travelling, and interviewing for the new position

UX Researcher & Designer • IptiQ By SwissRe

Zürich · Mar - Aug 2021 · Contract

Conducted user research and user tests for B2B2C projects for our partner IKEA. Reports with findings and recommendations for stakeholders. Designed in low/high fidelity, and clickable prototypes. Agile methodology.

UX Researcher & Designer • Muume AG

Zürich · Dec 2020 - Feb 2021 · Contract

Conducted observational research and designed digital interfaces for B2B and B2C softwares for commerce and multichannel payment solutions. Reports with findings and recommendations for stakeholders.

UX Researcher & Designer • Freelance

Zürich · Aug 2019 - Present

Planned and conducted user research for different SMBs. Developed product strategies, designed digital products in low/high fidelity, and interactive prototypes. Heuristic and accessibility evaluations.

Brand Ambassador • Lindt & Sprüngli

Zürich • Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Sales and customer experience. Collaborated with marketing. Support on store layout, stock, and visual merchandising.

Promoter • M.Prestige Promotions

Zürich • Sep 2017 - Sep 2018

Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Target sales for YSL, Dior, Chanel and customer experience. Trained on customer psychology and behavior from Brand Managers.

Studying german, and side jobs while relocating

Travel Designer • Ed è Subito Viaggi

Rome • Jan - Jul 2015

Designed tailored travel experiences, established long-term customer loyalty and returning customers. Identification of customer needs, customer experience and support.

EDUCATION

User Experience Nanodegree

Udacity • 2020

Created an end-to-end digital user experience ready for hand off.

• User research • Analysis and Synthesis of collected data • Design Sprint • Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype • Style guide and Design library • Usability test and Iterations.

User Experience Bootcamp

Interaction Design Foundation • 2019 - 2020

Designed a Project Management Web app through 1 to 1 mentorship sessions and guidance.

- User Research Design Sprint Sitemap Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype
- Style guide and Design library.

Travel Experience Design

Centro Turistico Studentesco - CTS, Italy • 2014

Lead the team for the design of a new travel itinerary in Brazil starting from the identification of a new travel concept until the prove of feasability.

• Market Research and Competitive Analysis • Travel Product ideation • Design of new itinerary • Prove of feasable implementation • Presentation of the project.

Bachelor of Humanities, Art

University of L'Aquila, Italy • 2008 - 2013

Major in Cultural and Environmental Heritage.

Erasmus Exchange

University of Zagreb, Croatia • 2012 - 2013

Master's Thesis in History of Architecture.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- Blockchain Overview: Business Foundations, Blockchain Training Alliance, 2021
- UX Management: Strategy and Tactics, Interaction Design Foundation, 2021.
- Conducting Usability Tests, Interaction Design Foundation, 2021
- Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner, Enterprise Design Thinking Co-Creator IBM 2021
- Information Visualization: Getting dashboards right, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Gamification: Creating addictive user experiences, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Affordances: Designing intuitive user interfaces, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Accessibility: How to design for all, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Emotional Design: How to make products people will love, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Agile Software Development, University of Minnesota, 2020
- Human Computer Interaction- HCI, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- UI Design Patterns for succesful software, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20
- User Research Methods and Best Practices, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Mobile UX Design, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Design Thinking, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Fundamentals of Graphic Design, typography and storytelling, Californian University of Arts, 2019.
- Store Layout & Visual Merchandising, London University of Arts, 2018
- Travel Experience Design, CTS, 2014.